

Vasan Routh

Full Stack Game Developer, Specializing in Networking

Love coding and playing games:) I am a versatile developer with 9+ years of experience in programming. Proficient in most major programming languages and comfortable picking up others if I haven't explored them already. I have released multiple games and I have had the opportunity to lead projects and manage teams of developers (Programming and cross-discipline). I enjoy sharing knowledge and having a meaningful impact on the projects I'm part of.



vasanrouth@gmail.com



Mumbai, India



linkedin.com/in/vasan-routh-9127731b6



github.com/vasanrouth



TECHNOLOGIES

General C, C++, C#, JavaScript (ES4-ES2022),

TypeScript, Java, Python, SQL, Bash, Android, ReactJS, ExpressJS, NodeJS, HTML,

CSS, PHP, Solidity

Art& UI Blender(modeling, texturing, animating),

Krita, Photoshop, Illustrator, UI (Adobe XD, Figma), Substance Painter, Alchemy, Marvellous Designer (Hair, Cloth simulation)

Games Engine& Graphics Unity (5+ years), UE5(1+ year), Godot(1+

year), OpenGL, WebGL

Cloud& Networking

AWS, Azure, Google Cloud Console, Firebase, Playafab, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, Docker, DevOps, REST APIs, Socket.IO, WebSocket, Photon, Mirror



WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Gameplay Engineer

MightyBeast Studios

05/2023 - Present Unity ,C#, NodeJS, AWS tools (Cognito, Lambda, DynamoDB, Gamelift, S3 bucket, Redshift), Mirror, ReactJS

chievements/Tasks

TODO (Hosting map servers. Buildings movement, Troop training, Combat mechanics,)

Dubai, UAE

Lead Game Developer

Daceg.Ltd 🗷

06/2022 - 03/2023

Unity , C#, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Photon Pun, Playfab, CloudRun, Moralis SDK, Hardhat, EtherJS, Solidity, Elasticsearch, LeanTween

London, England

Achievements/Tasks

- Worked with a team of 5 to build a mix of Card + RTS genre-type mobile games for both Android and IOS platforms, the game involves training
 troops and going for raids against other players like a typical RTS game,
- Automated the build and release by doing them cloud using Azure DevOps, Managed the team using Scrum by breaking down a project into smaller, manageable tickets,
- Collaborated closely with artists and designers to integrate assets and achieve visually stunning game world, Developed the server side
 components for high scalable multiplayer games.
- I have also implemented a lot of other modules like a notification system, loot boxes, settings panel, global chat, leaderboard, viewing player
 profile, Friends... etc (View the game)

Gameplay Engineer

Creatr Studios Inc. 🗷

01/2022 - 06/2023

Toronto, Canada

Unity ,C#, GraphQL, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Photon Pun, Playfab, CloudRun, Enjin SDK, Facebook SDK, Azure VM, LeanTween

Achievements/Tasks

- Worked on this 8-bit style multiplayer treasure-digging game, that has multiple game modes, like memorizing shapes, and solving math in a PVP
 environment, where the quick solver gets to dig faster and reach the treasure at the bottom,
- The game interacts with Enjin cloud using GraphQL queries and mutations, these are performed safely in the Google Cloud Run(NodeJS) platform, and player data is stored in Playfab,
- I also worked on implementing globally viewable player win streaks leaderboard, In-app purchases, Importing NFTs to game using Enjin wallet,
- The game uses the photon cloud as a networking framework that transmits player inputs through RPC calls to keep the game state in Sync, these calls are also backed up in the cloud so that even if both players quit and rejoin the room will still be live. (View the game).



Game Designer & Developer

FrostDrakeGames 🗷

09/2020 - 02/2022

Unity ,C#, GraphQL, NodeJS, Photon Network, Playfab, CloudRun, Enjin SDK, Facebook SDK, Blender, Substance Painter, Alchemy

Bangalore, India

Achievements/Tasks

- Created a turn-based strategy game built for mobile devices called <u>Gambit</u>. Which also has modes like 1v1 skill-based bet matches, The Game runs
 on Unity and makes use of Playfab to store player data, authentication(Facebook, Play games), analytics,
- Interacts with Enjin Cloud to make bets in the game, all the backend computations are processed by Google Cloud Functions and Playfab
 Cloudscript, I have also added clans and a global chat feature to make it more social,
- I created couple of 3D models with animation in Blender, for Stylized texturing used Substance Painter, Alchemy (ArtStation).
- Created a <u>Kickstarter</u> campaign and used Unity Cinemachine to shoot a perfect trailer (<u>View trailer</u>) for this game and did the postprocessing sound
 effects in AfterEffects. (<u>View gameplay</u>)

Unity AR Developer

JIPMER 🗷

05/2018 - 07/2020

Unity, C#, Firebase, Python, Vuforia SDK, ARCore

Pondicherry, India

Achievements/Tasks

- Developed an Indoor navigation AR mobile application that uses RSSI WiFi fingerprinting to navigate users to the selected destination without a
 need for GPS.
- Engineered efficient navigation by implementing the A* pathfinding algorithm using C#, optimizing route calculations for dynamic indoor
 environments,
- Leveraged Firebase's real-time database to enable seamless data synchronization, facilitating collaborative and synchronized experiences within the AR application,
- Orchestrated the technical aspects, leading the team through AR implementation, algorithm integration, and Firebase utilization, ensuring a
 cohesive and functional end product.

Full-stack web developer

Ignite Skylabs 🗷

08/2017 - 05/2020

Pondicherry, India

HTML, CSS, ReactJS, NodeJS, Azure, Firebase, PHP, MySQL, MongoDB, Java, Android, Python, Flask, Django, C#, Fusion360, Verilog HDL

Achievements/Tasks

- This is an LLC that I formed while in college. Where I created web and mobile apps for startups and big corporations like NCR, GE India and HP
 India..etc with a team of 3,
- Some of my commercial projects include building a <u>Shopping app</u>, <u>Medical appointment booking</u>, <u>Education Apps</u>..etc.,

Pondicherry, India

• I Own 10+ IPs for some of the embedded projects like (IV Drip monitoring systems, Limb Reconstruction Systems,.. etc). Also got a couple of National awards from Gov of India.



OTHER PROJECTS

Bubble Shooter (06/2020 - 02/2021) 🛂

Tricky Bounce - Brick Breaker (03/2021 - 04/2021) 🗹



EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Electronics & Communication Engg.
Pondicherry University

05/2017 - 06/2021

Diploma in Computer Science AHSS, Pondicherry

03/2015 - 03/2017

Pondicherry, India



CERTIFICATIONS

AWS in Multiplayer Games (10/2023 - 10/2023)

Course on Using DynamoDB, Cognito, and Lambda to build a basic player management system.

AWS Certified Developer Associate 2023 (08/2023 - 10/2023)

Course on using AWS tools and insights of each service which is very helpful for a developer for real world implementations.